<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="hello">Choose one of the features below.</string>

    <string name="app_name">Revolutionary War Trivia</string>
    <string name="description_logo">Demo</string>

    <string name="description_about">About</string>
    <string name="description_home">Home</string>
    <string name="description_search">Search</string>
    <string name="description_feature2">Feature 2</string>
    <string name="description_feature3">Feature 3</string>
    <string name="description_feature4">Feature 4</string>
    <string name="description_feature5">Feature 5</string>
    <string name="description_feature6">Feature 6</string>

    <string name="title_about">About</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_search">Search</string>
    <string name="title_feature2">Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_feature3">People</string>
    <string name="title_feature4">Places</string>
    <string name="title_feature5">Weapons</string>
    <string name="title_feature6">Quotes</string>

    <string name="default_intro">This is the default content view for an activity. Be sure to change your activity\'s onCreate method. Use setContentView on a custom layout.</string>
    <string name="feature2_intro">Feature 2 content goes here.</string>
    <string name="feature3_intro">Feature 3 content goes here.</string>
    <string name="feature4_intro">Feature 4 content goes here.</string>
    <string name="feature5_intro">Feature 5 content goes here.</string>
    <string name="feature6_intro">Feature 6 content goes here.</string>

    <string name="about_intro">This app is a demo to show you how to do an Android app based on the Dashboard pattern that has been used in apps like Twitter, Google IO, and Evernote.</string>
    <string name="search_intro">Content for the Search page goes here.</string>
   
    <!-- Quiz Activity Strings -->
    <string name="builder_title">What Type of Questions Do You Want?</string>
    
    <!-- american figure summaries -->
 
    
     <string name="arnold">
     \n\n     Benedict Arnold was born on January 14th, 1741 in the bustling Noriwch, Connecticut to Hannah Walterman King and Benedict Arnold. He was one of the only two children from Arnold and King marriage to survive into adulthood, the other being his sister, Hannah. Sadly the other children succumbed to various illnesses such as yellow fever and died at young ages. As a boy Arnold\'s family became moderately wealthy and sent their son to private schools afforded him a good well rounded education, learning a touch of Latin and writing very well. Arnold was also known for his ability to make impulse decisions for good and bad, sometimes going against his parents best wishes. This was evidenced when at the age of 15 Arnold ran away from home and joined the Connecticut army to counteract the French invasion that would take place at Lake George. Eventually becoming tired of the fight, Arnold deserted the Connecticut army, grew up and matured.  
     \n     At adulthood he moved to New Haven, Connecticut and began to work as a bookseller and druggist. During this time Arnold also obtained large portions of property and occasionlly partook in trades with the West Indies. In 1775 when the battle of Lexington and Concord reached Arnold\'s doorstep in New Haven he was appointed control of roughly 400 men and received orders to march on Fort Ticonderoga. Joining General Montgomery, Horatio Gates, and others, Arnold fought for the fort and succeeded in taking by May 10th 1775. After the battle everyone was thrilled with the capture of the fort and on February 19, 1777 George Washington named five new generals to the Continental army. Arnold, at the time a brigadier-general, was passed over in these promotions.
     \n     In January of 1778 Arnold suffered a bad leg wound in the Battle of Quebec and was assinged by Washington to look after the city of Philidelphia. In his time in there Arnold got into many quarrels with several generals and started to associate with Tory sympathizers (Americans who supported the British during the American Revolution).\n\n     In July of 1780 Arnold directly sought control of the prestigious military school West Point. Then he proceeded to hand it over to the British. However, the capture of Major John Andre of the British Army by the Americans voided Arnold\'s plans. Hearing of this news Arnold quickly fled to the British in New York and ironically was handed a position of brigadier-general. From this moment on Arnold was considered by most Americans to be a traitor to his country and any mention of his name meant treason.\n\n     As for Arnold himself, he moved to London and was involved in the mercantile business. He died in 1792 when he lost a duel to the Earl of Landerdale over a comment that the Earl made about him in the House of Lords. </string>
    
    <string name="clinton">
     \n\n    James Clinton was born on August 9th, 1736 in Ulster County New York and was the fourth son of Colonel Charles Clinton. He came from a long line of notable family members who either had prominent positions in government or the army. His grandfather James Clinton served in Oliver Cromwell\'s New Model Army in the English Civil War, his brother George went on to serve as governor of New York and vice president of the United States from 1805-1812.
     \n     As a young man he had a keen interest in weapons and knowing how to defend himself against potential Indian attacks. This kind of upbringing and know how was only natural considering his family history.
     \n     By 1758 with French and Indian War in full swing, Clinton, who was now 21 years of age, fought along side his father and brother in an effort to help take Fort Frontenac. In this battle James and George were able to combine their skills to capture a French vessel. By the end of the French and Indian War in 1763 James Clinton had become a captain in the army(1759), and had roughly 200 men under his command.\n\n     Shortly after the war ended Clinton married Mary Dewitt and in 1769 would have a child by the name of DeWitt Clinton. The boy would go on to become the Governor of New York and also a United States senator. With war over for the moment Clinton took up farming and stuck true to his beliefs in personal liberties.\n\n    Throughout the next years Clinton would begin to participate in the war for independence, fighting in various battles including the battle of Quebec, which was ultimately a retreating effort under General Montgomery.\n\n     In 1777, Clinton now a brigadier general took part in the Saratoga Campaign to thwart the plans of the British general Sir Henry Clinton from rescuing British General John Burgoyne. Initially he and his troops were successful in repelling the oncoming attack from the British but in reality that were outmanned and outgunned. Some estimates say that the American troops were outnumbered by as many as 2400 men. Because of this scenario the forts were overun and the troops had to retreat. During this escape James suffered a bayonet wound from an opposing soldier.
     \n     Perhaps one of his most pivotal actions came in 1779 when Clinton led a journey down the Susquehanna River and had his soldiers engineer a dam. Now called General Clinton\'s Dam, the structure made it possible for Clinton\'s troops to combine with the forces of General John Sullivan at Tioga, New York. The increased number of troops helped provided a strong victory at the Battle of Newtown, beating the Indians and the Tories. Later on this march and decisive victory would be known as the "Sullivan-Clinton" Campaign. After this undertaking Clinton joined forces with Washington during the siege of Yorktown and was there when Cornwallis finally surrendered on October 19th, 1781 after 21 days of fighting.
     \n     After the war Clinton was still actively involved in the nations matters. He voted on the ratification of the constitution(voted nay thinking this would give the government too much power) and also helped define the border between New York and Pennslyvania. Following the death of his brother George in 1812, James Clinton died on September 22, 1812 at his home in upstate New York. He was 79 years old.
      </string>
    
    <string name="gates">
    \n      Horatio Gates was born on July 26th, 1727 in Maldon, England to parents Robert and Dorothea Gates. From an early age he entered the English army and expressed and because of his gallant duties was premoted swiftly through the ranks. At the age of 22 he travelled to America as a volunteer to the governor of Novia Scotia, Edward Cornwallis, the uncle of eventual General Charles Cornwallis of the British. Just as Gates arrived in America the Seven Years War was beginning to take place. Eager to lend his duties to help out in any way, Gates served under General Edward Braddock in an effort to gain control of the Ohio Valley. This undertaking included other notable leaders such as Thomas Gage, Charles Lee, Daniel Morgan, and George Washington. Although Gates did not see any direct military action during this expedition he made a favorable impression on the other members of the party with his skills in military administration. When the exploration was finished Gates had a brief stint of service under the command of British General John Stanwix. There he held the rank of brigadier general and had the honor of informing of mother England of military victories and the capture of Martinque in the West Indies. Upon hearing this news England promoted Gates to the position of major. However, the war was winding down and there was not enough time for future ranking advancements. 
    \n      During the time between the Seven Years War and the American Revolution Gates moved back to England around Novemeber of 1755 and wanted to start a family. He married Elizabeth Phillips and in 1758 fathered a son by the name of Robert Gates. While he was happy with his family situation Gates began to become dissatisfied with the military system(advancement required money and influence) and Britain\'s rigid class structure. This was enough to make Gates sell his position of Major in the military and move his family to America.
    \n      Now in America Gates and his family bought a humble plantation in Virginia and re-contacted Geroge Washington. In May of 1775 with the threat of on all out war with the British growing closer Gates could not sit idely. He rode to Mount Vernon and volunteered his services to Washington in any way he could help. Because of his previously demonstrated skills in the Ohio Valley expedition this made Gates a favorite for a high ranking position in Washington\'s plans. And high ranking he became. On June 17th of 1775 Horatio Gates was recognized as the commanding adjunct General of the Continental Army. He was the first adjunct General in United States history. George Washington was the commander and chief of the army. 
    \n      The year of 1776 was quite an eventful one for the 30 year old Gates. He was part of the Saratoga Campaign to defend many cities from being taken by the British. In the Battle of Trenton an odd scenario played out where Gates\' troops were fighting alongside of Washington but Gates himself was not there. When questioned about this Gates claimed that he was too ill to participate in the attack and went on to meet with the Continental Congress instead. At this point in the war many, including Gates himself, felt like he should be the commander and chief of the army and not Washington. However any critics of Washington were persuaded after his decisive victories at Trenton and Princeton.
    \n      On August 19th Gates led the Nortern wing of the army on an assault and defeated British General Burgoyne. This was a great victory that Gates and his fellow superiors took credit for. However, several men including Benedict Arnold thought this credit was undue. Arnold led other men into the field of battle against Gates wishes. Because of Gates defensive minded strategy Arnold often referred to him as, "Granny Gates." 
    \n      Other notable events involving Gates were his attempts to supercede Washington in control when the Continnetal Army was temporarily unsuccessful. The process involved Gates sending a letters directly to Congress instead of Washington. Then Congress named Gates to the Board of War, a civilian position higher than Washington. When confronted by Washington and his supporters about this issue Gates relinquised the position on the board. These series of events is now called the "Conway Cabal."
    \n      In one of his last military inolvements Gates led his men into the Battle of Camden against Charles Cornwallis. Gates was defeated, losing 1000 men to capture and others thought that he overestimated the enemy. Because of the Camden disaster Gates was questioned by a board of inquiry. It was thought that he would never be placed in a position for battle again but in 1783 he rejoined Washington\'s staff in New York. This position did not last long due to his retirement in 1784. In the end Gates died on April 10th, 1806 and is currently buired in the Trinity Church graveyard on Wall Street. </string>
    
    <string name="greene">
    nathaniel greene HERE </string>
    
  
    
    <string name="rohowe">
    robert howe HERE </string>
    
    <string name="knox">
    henry knox HERE </string>
    
    <string name="lee">
    charles lee HERE </string>
    
    <string name="linc">
    benjamin lincoln HERE </string>
    
    <string name="mar">
    francis marion HERE </string>
    
    <string name="monty">
    richard montgomery HERE </string>
    
    <string name="revere">
    paul revere HERE </string>
    
    <string name="shu">
    philip shuyler HERE </string>
   
    
    <string name="sull">
    john sullivan HERE </string>
    
    <string name="sumt">
    thomas sumter HERE </string>
    
    <string name="thomas">
    john thomas HERE </string>
    
    <string name="warren">
    joseph warren HERE </string>
    
    <string name="wash">
    george washington HERE </string>
    
    <!-- British military figures -->
    
    <string name="george">
    the king HERE </string>
    <string name="amherst">
    sir jeffrey amherst HERE </string>
    <string name="conway">
    henry conway HERE </string>
    <string name="gage">
    thomas gage HERE </string>
    <string name="hclinton">
    sir henry clinton HERE </string>
 
    <string name="whowe">
    william howe HERE </string>
    <string name="boyd">
    sir robert boyd HERE </string>
    <string name="arb">
    mariot abuthnot HERE </string>
    <string name="burg">
    john burgoyne HERE </string>
   
    <string name="corn">
    charles cornwallis HERE </string>
    <string name="graves">
    samuel graves HERE </string>
    <string name="faw">
    sir william fawcett HERE </string>

    <string name="green">
    william green HERE </string>
    <string name="hald">
    fredrick haldimand HERE </string>
    <string name="phill">
    william philips HERE </string>
    <string name="rihowe">
    richard howe HERE </string>
    
    
    <!-- French military figures -->
    <string name="louis">
     king louis XVI </string>
    
    <string name="gravier">
     charles gravier </string>
    <string name="sart">
     antoine de sartine </string>
    <string name="lafy">
     lafayette </string>
    <string name="bourbon">
     bourbon </string>
    <string name="hector">
     charles hector comte </string>
    <string name="grasse">
     paul de grasse </string>
    <string name="vim">
     de vimuer </string>
     
    

</resources>
